SUMMARY

Motivated, teamwork-oriented, and responsible Data Analyst with strong quantitative experience in strategic problem solving and data management. Highly inquisitive, passionate, and capable in data retrieval, manipulation, and visualization. Enthusiastic about statistics and drawing meaningful insights. Familiar with a wide range of technologies including SQL, Python, Excel, Tableau, and more.

SKILLS

- Data Management: Data Quality Assessment, Data Analysis, Pattern & Trend Identification, Visualization of Data Insights
- Languages: Python, SQL, R, HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Databases: Microsoft SQL Server, Oracle, Postgres
- Software: Microsoft Office Suite, Google Suite, Tableau, Git\GitHub
- Frameworks: Django
- Certifications: CompTIA A+, CompTIA Network+, CompTIA Project+

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Bachelor of Science: Information Technology – Data Analysis/Data Management Western Governors University - Salt Lake City, UT

vvesterii Governois Oniversity - Gait Lake City, OT

Women in Technology Club

Associate of Applied Science: Computer Programming Wake Technical Community College - Raleigh, NC

Phi Theta Kappa; National Technical Honor Society

12/2021

05/2019

EXPERIENCE

Software Tester / SOLID - Fairfax, VA

02/2019 - 11/2019

- Leveraged programming skills to update databases and CRUD system, fix bugs, make improvements within the web application, and give valuable feedback
- Utilized data analysis to monitor process efficiencies and identify data integrity exceptions.
- Collaborated on contracted projects that involved, gathering, summarizing, and analyzing data for multiple government clients using critical thinking skills
- Assisted project coordinator with generating highly detailed reports with KPI metrics to be sent to upper management and the clients
- Tested multiple versions of company's web application, taking into consideration unique browser platforms and most common devices used by the users
- Experienced in utilizing JIRA for test management and providing supporting documentation for all bugs found.

Private Tutor / CEO 05/2015 - 08/2016

- Offered up to 60-minute sessions in a variety of subjects: English (Reading, Writing, and Reading Comprehension), Math (Basic Math, Pre-Algebra, Algebra), Science, Social Sciences
- Differentiated between instruction styles and tools to facilitate desired results based on students learning abilities
- Mentored clients of effective studying and test taking techniques

 Delivered desired results of services rendered as 100% of mentees were able to improve grades and pass their classes.

Customer Service Representative / Xerox-Humana - Cary, NC

09/2013 - 04/2015

- Recorded full and accurate customer data by utilizing the company's call management system
- Consistently received 98% to 100% rating in audited customer service evaluations due to active listening and problem-solving skills
- Succeeded in providing outstanding service to 100 + customers daily across 3 different departments: Billing and Enrollment, Claims, and Dental.
- Educated customers on special pricing opportunities and company offerings.
- De-escalated problematic customer concerns, maintaining calm, friendly demeanor.
- Maintained knowledge of current promotions, exchange guidelines, payment policies and security practices.

IMPORTANT LINKS

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/tashiana-romero

Portfolio: https://anarome.github.io

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Certifications: CompTIA A+, CompTIA Network+, CompTIA Project